Guide to the Patriotic Envelope Collection [1861-1865], 1898 PR 117
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Civil War Envelopes, 1
  - Zouaves: [Zouave camp] (Offsite-box 7, Item 6)
    Zouave soldiers seated in front of tent. White envelope with blue ink. Image on left with indications for name and address.
  - Zouaves: Washington via Baltimore (Offsite-box 7, Item 22)
    Zouave soldier holding an American flag and a bayonet looks at a sign with "Washington via Baltimore" on it. The Capitol is in the background. White envelope with red and blue ink. Image on left side.
  - Zouaves: A Fireman Zouave putting out secession. (Offsite-box 7, Item 31)
    A Zouave fireman spraying a person in the face with smoke billowing in the background. Cream envelope with black ink. Image on left side.
  - Zouaves: When thus our hosts go proudly forth, Let foes beware the Spirit of the North! (Offsite-box 7, Item 27)
    Zouave soldier carrying the American flag and a short knife. He is on a battlefield with explosions behind him. White envelope with multi-colored inks. Image on left side.
  - Zouaves: Reg't., Co. Capt. (Offsite-box 7, Item 14)
    Uniformed officer with long bayonet in uniform. It suggests the soldier is a Zouave. White envelope with red, blue and yellow ink. Image on left side and there is a form to fill in the address.
  - Zouaves: The School of the Fire Zouave. (Offsite-box 7, Item 20)
    A fireman standing next to a hose, while others toil in the background. White envelope with blue ink. Image on left side.
    Creator: Tilton, J.E. & Co.
- Series II: Spanish American War Envelopes, 2
  - Portraits (Offsite-box 7)
    See Also Box 8
  - Subjects (Offsite-box 7)
- Oversize Materials, [1861-1865], 1898; 3
  - Civil War Envelopes, [1861-1865] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
  - Civil War pictoral lettersheets, [1861-1865] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
  - Civil War Ephemera, [1861-1865] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
  - Spanish American War Envelopes, [1898] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
  - Spanish American War pictoral lettersheets, [1898] (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
  - Civil War unbound envelope scrapbook, 1891 (Offsite-box 8)